TYLERCHONG9641@GMAIL.COM

TYLER CHONG

SUMMARY

Tyler is a full-stack developer who has ten years of experience working in a variety of technologies for clients such as React, AngularJS, Vue, Node.js, and PHP. He has a Bachelor's and Masters degree in Computer Science and a strong portfolio of work to demonstrate his skills. He prides himself on his extreme attention to detail, efficiency, and delivering high-value work.

As a software developer with over 10 years of experience, he is comfortable with a myriad of tools and libraries (React 16, Redux, Redux-saga, Vue.js/Vuex, TypeScript) and more than proficient with accessible HTML5, responsive CSS, and JavaScript on both the front and back end.

He's also handy with Node.js, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Express, Sass, and whatever else is needed to spin up a development environment, run tests, or deploy components.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto

Apr 2007 - Oct 2008, Toronto

Master of Computer Science

- Software Engineering
- Cyber Security

University of Toronto, Toronto

Apr 2002 - Oct 2006, Toronto

Bachelor of Computer Science

- Computer Science
- Software Engineering
- OOP(Object-oriented programming) languages
- Cyber Security

SKILLS

Web Programming: React, Vue, Angular, Node, TypeScript, Javascript, PHP, Laravel

Mobile Programming: React Native, Xamarins, Swift

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon DynamoDB

APIs: Social Media, Google APIs, Web API/JSON/SOAP, OAuth

Testing: Unit Testing, E2E Testing

Platforms: Linux, MacOS, Windows, Docker

Tools: Git, IDE, Amazon Web Service

EXPERIENCE

Wealthsimple, Toronto - Remote Full Stack Developer

February 2019 - June 2020

- Handled the full-stack development on the Wealthsimple for the Advisors product (Wealthsimple's B2B offering that enables financial advisors to focus on delivering value to their clients).
- Implemented white labeling: a key player to our internal design system of themeable React components, eliminating theme-related bugs.
- Implemented the associate role: this feature saves advisors time by allowing them to invite colleagues to securely manage their clients.
- Rewrote the "log in as client" functionality ("impersonation"): the feature allows advisors to perform actions on behalf of their clients the way the client would themselves.

Mitre Media, Toronto - Remote Full Stack Developer

December 2017 - January 2019

- Reduced server response time significantly using different caching strategies, assets management, and database querying optimization in MySQL.
- Architected and implemented a front end system for React Application with Material UI and Styled Components and animation using React Pose.
- Incorporated ReactJS strategies such as higher-order components, render props, and global state management using Apollo client caching.
- Proposed and developed GraphQL endpoint for its advantage of a single source of data while developing GraphQL schema foundation in Rails and reusable Querying/Mutation structure in React.

Uberflip, Toronto - Remote Full Stack Developer

January 2017 - November 2017

- Administered a reusable in-house web app to process issues and commit data from Redmine and Jira for SR&ED review using a pure JavaScript solution.
- Promoted code quality and standards by implementing various custom Git commit hooks.
- Employed PHP mass detector and PHP linting tools to maintain code integrity and visibility among the development team.

Cardero-X, Ottawa - Full Stack Developer

March 2014 - December 2016

- Implemented a redesigned version of the public website.
- Created multiple landing pages with reusable components.
- Created responsive emails with MJML for use in Drip campaigns.
- Analyzed data in Google Analytics and provided new insights.

• Implemented a signup gateway with the main app, with Google and Facebook social sign-in.

APPCOM, Montreal - Software Engineer

January 2012 - February 2014

- Developed several mobile client applications in Swift as part of a software development agency.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of server API using PHP and Laravel.
- Troubleshot and optimized based on evolving requirements.

TEAM ATOMIC INC, Toronto - Software Engineer

April 2010 - December 2011

- Created pixel-perfect web development from PSD mockups; including custom CSS, HTML, and JavaScript.
- Solved client problems as efficiently as possible.
- Developed the business; performed client acquisition and administration.

FUNDING MATTERS, Toronto - Software Engineer

January 2009 - March 2010

- Developed the Funding Matters Inc.'s website and sister company websites.
- Designed, developed, and enhanced the websites for Funding Matters'
- Created the custom Content Management System design and development in WordPress and ProcessWire.
- Designed and developed accessible websites as per the web content accessibility guidelines (WCAG 2.0) for government-funded websites.

SOCIAL PROFILES

FaceBook: https://www.facebook.com/tyler.chong.1614460

Twitter: https://twitter.com/TylerChona9641

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-chong-203972199/

Github: https://github.com/roque707Dev

StackOverFlow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/12756481/tyler-chong?tab=profile

Portfolio: http://tylerchong.herokuapp.com/